Hurry up!
Look! It's Jupiter!
The largest planet in the Solar System.
Dad.
There is an eye on Jupiter.
That's a huge windstorm on Jupiter.
What's a windstorm?
Jupiter is like a huge balloon.
Composed of 90% hydrogen.
Grandpa, what's hydrogen?
What is hydrogen?
It's the fuel for Dad's rocket.
Hydrogen is
the fuel for Dad's rocket.
I see.
Liu Qi.
Yes?
A day may come
when you can see Jupiter without a telescope...
that's when dad will come back.
Where are you going?
Dad is going on a mission.
The most important mission in the world.
After I leave,
you'll be Liu Qi's only custodian.
You shall obtain the right
of underground city residency
without drawing the lots.
And it is the only way
to ensure that both you and Liu Qi
will survive.
This is the only choice--
That's enough. I get it.
Father.
Sorry.
At first
nobody cared about this disaster.
It's just another wildfire.
Another drought.
Another extinction of species.
Another vanishing city.
Until everyone is entwined with this disaster.
The Sun is rapidly degenerating and expanding.
The Sun will engulf Earth in 100 years.
The Solar System will
no longer exist in 300 years.
To face this coming cataclysmic catastrophe,
mankind united like never seen before.
In order to maximize the chance of human survival,
the United Earth Government
or the UEG decided to propel Earth out of
the Solar System to fly towards our new home
located 4.2 light years away.
This mighty and enduring
- human migration
- is named as the Wandering Earth Project.
Mankind will devote every possible resource
to construct 10,000 Earth Engines
on the planet's surface
to propel Earth out of the Solar System.
The height of every Propulsion Engine
is 11,000 meters.
They will provide a total
of 150 trillion propulsive force for Earth.
Salute!
The construction of Navigation Platform
International Space Station
will be completed early this month.
There are 311 Chinese senior pilots
- and 709 engineers that were selected.
Ignite.
Meanwhile,
to safeguard Earth's trajectory,
the United Earth Government consolidated
global astronautical capabilities
and spent 30 years to build the Navigation
Platform International Space Station.
The Navigation Platform
International Space Station will travel
with a relative position of 100,000 km to Earth.
It will provide warnings, navigations,
and communications for Earth.
Centrifugal drive activated.
Worldwide sea level will rise 300 meters within 10 years.
Haikou and Zhanjiang of our country
will be attacked by the tsunami first.
To deal with the continuous
deteriorating condition,
UEG constructed one adjacent city
beneath each Earth Engine.
Before Earth's arrival at its new home,
these will be the only refuge for mankind.
The right to underground residency
will be obtained by drawing lots.
The lottery result can't be transferred,
borrowed, or gifted,
till now. Mankind,
a tiny tribe in the Solar System,
will be embarking upon 2,500 years
- of wandering voyage.
The surface temperature will drop to
minus 70 degrees Celsius this year.
All surface residents from different
- Slowly.
- Don't push!
Dad will fly up into the sky
and turn into a star
to always watch over you.
Dad.
Are you really going to turn into a star?
Of course.
From now on, you just have to count.
Three.
Two.
One.
Look up!
You will see Dad.
Good bye, Solar System.
Au revoir, système solaire.
Welcome to The Morning News.
Today's headlines are...
During the arrival of spring,
the first batch of personnel
on the Navigation Platform will be returning.
Completing 15 to 20 years of station duties.
All underground citizens of the globe
are eagerly anticipating their arrivals.
Therefore...
GRANDPA. I'VE DECIDED TO LEAVE.
DON'T WORRY. LIU QI.
Anticipating.
Spring breeze has arrived.
The spring is near.
The yearly planning starts with spring.
It's full of effort.
It's full of hope.
Tell us, monitor.
How do you define hope?
Hope is precious like a diamond for our time.
Hope is the only direction of our home.
Well said. Please seat.
Han Duoduo, do you have any thoughts?
I have nothing to say.
I just want to take a look outside,
but it's too dangerous out.
Xiao Ming, be seated. Class.
Don't panic. It's just a display malfunction.
Go. Let's go.
Xiao Ming, go back.
Stay in order.
Did you do this?
Shut up! Let's move!
Teacher.
Han Duoduo has run away!
- Happy New Year!
Hu Kou. Committee is giving out dumplings tonight?
All you think about is food!
Where is Grandpa's vehicle pass?
I've got it.
Shall we grab the dumplings before we leave?
Eat dirt! Don't go then!
Liar!
You said you'll take me outside.
All personnel, return to your post.
Durian-flavored dried Earthworms!
What are you looking at?
It's just a day trip.
What's the rush?
That's what it is to you.
I'm not planning on returning.
Get moving!
Going nowhere without the suits.
You had the mahjong I needed,
why didn't you discard it?
Isn't bunny girl's
tail soft and sweet?
Aren't we meant to be each others' angel?
What are you doing here? It's the New Year!
How cheeky you are!
Hey.
Go.
Yi Ge.
Are the suits ready?
The stuff I want?
It's fairly new.
All checked.
Usable.
And I got you skewers too.
Eat while it is warm.
Good.
Grab your thermal suits.
How old are you?
Check out this tag Yi Ge made!
Just like the real thing.
Yours.
Thanks, Yi Ge.
Return the suits tomorrow.
Thanks. Yi Ge. See you.
Hurry up and move.
Didn't you say you are not coming back?
Wait.
Not coming back?
Are these all you paid me?
For two of my thermal suits?
Yi Ge, I'll make it up when I get back.
For years, I, Yi Ge, have been known
for honest trading only.
No credits given!
Yi Ge, I really need to go out today.
What for?
Just stay here with your sister for the new year.
Hey, boss, look!
Hyper?
You stinky repairman.
I dare you! Use it here...
Duoduo, get down.
I want him dead!
Dear friends.
Let's open the door and embrace the spring.
Joy shall follow you when you see one.
A New Year,
with our heads up and walking tall,
marching toward to the next spectacular chapter.
- Excuse us.
I dare you not to come back!
What?
Will they report us?
These were obtained illegally.
They'll expose themselves if they report.
Well...
This Spring Festival.
You will spend it with me outside.
Please check your thermal suit and helmet.
Please wait there.
Miss, can I chew gum with my helmet on?
- Chew what?
- Shut up and come over!
- In three days, we'll swing past Jupiter.
- Attention!
All transportation communication systems
must be turned on all the time.
Follow evacuation instructions at any time.
Please pay attention to reversing.
Oh, my.
Look at yourself.
Is it your first time outside, too?
Haven't you been outside before?
It wasn't this crowded last time.
You are such a liar.
How long will it take to get to the surface?
It's 5 km,
so at least 15 minutes.
Okay.
This is a communication device.
Press once to sync with the transporter.
Twice for regional broadcast.
Three times for the private channel.
Once outside,
stay close to me.
Don't run around.
Are you afraid?
Surface level reached.
All personnel, please be ready.
Let's go!
Enough looking around?
I sneaked out.
Am I getting expelled by the school?
Have you already been kicked out of your unit?
Nonsense.
Which one is Transporter 373?
Duoduo, come over!
- Give me grandpa's vehicle pass.
- Here.
Han Ziang,
senior driver.
Beijing No. 3 Transportation Division reminds you.
Routes are countless.
Safety is foremost.
With unregulated driving,
your loved ones might end up in tears.
Clutch.
Gear.
What the...
Can you drive, Hu Kou?
This transporter is not for everyone!
It requires at least five years of training.
I am genius enough just to make it move.
- Okay?
Genius.
Step on the clutch, hand on the gear, then move.
Heavy step, light hand and no commotion.
Watch out! There are others ahead!
Shit! Fuck!
Watch out!
The world outside is huge!
What are you yelling about? So embarrassing!
Such strong winds today.
Why are they mining these mountains?
For fuel.
Heavy fusion propulsion technology.
Basically.
Basically, it's burning rocks.
The Earth Engine!
These are Propulsion Engines.
There are 10,000 of them around the globe,
made for pushing Earth forward.
This isn't the most gigantic one.
Those Torque Engines along the equator,
they are the real giants.
Synchronal translation is on.
Buddy.
Happy retirement.
One more day until I go home.
Don't mess up my last dignity.
Save this moonshine for yourself.
I will store it somewhere safe for you.
Save it for your farewell party.
We are not getting another chance
once we hibernate.
Don't you know
how vodka was smuggled up
during Gagarin's time?
We'll be entering Jupiter's orbit today, right?
Yes, we have already stood by for
Emergency Protocol No. 3.
Something doesn't feel right.
There's no other way. Earth can't
leave the Solar System
without utilizing Jupiter's gravity.
It is a risk we must take.
God will bless us.
Once this is over, you can return home.
It's the last procedure for daily inspection.
Check the Centrifugal Drive Control unit.
Record the temperatures
of Centrifugal axle bearings.
Understood.
Liu Peiqiang has completed handover procedure.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
Until today,
you have accumulated a resting time
of 12 years and 3 days in total.
An accumulated shift of 5 years and 14 days total.
We are grateful for your contributions
for the past 17 years.
Congratulations on your duty completion
and journey home tomorrow.
Brother.
See you on Earth three years later.
Go catch up with your son.
You haven't spoken to him for almost a decade.
See you on Earth.
Bro.
You'll be spending
the next three years with me now.
Jupiter's gravitational spike detected.
Earth's trajectory is off course by 9.23 degrees
due to Jupiter's gravitational spike.
The probability of colliding
with Jupiter increases.
Analyzing data collected.
Transmitting to the UEG.
Disaster warning protocols activated.
There's a supply depot 50 km ahead.
Once we get there,
you go back by yourself.
Catch the earliest shuttle back
so grandpa won't worry about us.
Oh, come on.
You would be clenched by the collar
once your dad gets back.
I'm a genius. No one is capable of clenching me.
What the...
Car inspection.
How did you get in here?
Unregulated...
Unregulated driving.
Unregulated?
You committed thievery!
I didn't steal. I just borrowed it.
It's my grandpa's vehicle pass.
Nonsense. All transporters belong to
the UEG as public properties.
It's not up to your grandpa!
What are you doing?
It's way past bedtime!
Sir.
I'm just getting to know new friends.
More friends, more options.
Hand over.
You think it is yours?
Hit the sack.
Have a nice stroll.
I am Tim.
My dad is from Beijing
and my mom is from Melbourne.
A Chinese and Australian joint product.
Come on, I was just joking.
Let's shake hands?
Hello.
Joint product.
It hurts. Let go of me.
It hurts!
Name of the visitor?
Han Ziang.
I'm here for my grandson.
Someone's getting bailed.
Sir.
My grandson is a mechanic trainee.
He just wanted to touch the real thing.
May you go easy on him.
Transporters are highly valuable public property.
Lending out your vehicle pass privately
is also a serious offense.
This is good stuff.
It has a collection of hotties
from the past 50 years.
It's all in.
Oh, well.
Same old trick.
Stop wobbling, old man!
What old man?
I wouldn't be here if it wasn't for you.
Running away from home.
You're too old to be running away.
He is your father anyhow.
Where are you going to hide?
You even brought your little sister out?
Outside is dangerous!
And you!
You've learned to steal!
You stole my pass!
Should you do whatever
your brother told you to do?
Are you dumb?
I didn't intend to bring her along.
But she was begging me--
As a brother...
to take her.
Liu Qi! You liar!
Here she goes again.
Nicely said!
Ignore senior's advice--
Mind your own business!
Don't take it out on the wall.
Take it out on me if you dare.
What the...
Earthquake!
Shi San Yao!
I won!
Open the door!
Anyone?
Here!
- Hurry up! Open the door!
- Here!
Warning.
Earth Engine system failing.
Total, 121 facilities.
Correction.
1,112 facilities.
3,319 facilities.
Don't leave me!
Help! Is anyone there?
My mom needs me and my kid...
I don't even have a kid yet!
Hey!
Please help me, man.
- Hu Kou.
- Come on.
- Hu Kou, come back.
- Come here.
Grab the key.
The key! The key is pinned underneath.
What's this? You can't pull this apart!
Hurry up!
Wait for me.
Engine No. 7 has stopped.
Engine No. 3 has stopped.
Get the chief engineer! Quick!
Due to Jupiter's gravitational spike,
Earth's propulsion has been halved.
Torques lost completely.
In 37 hours 4 minutes 12 seconds,
the Earth will collide with Jupiter.
Han Ziang, senior driver.
Beijing No. 3 Transportation Division reminds you.
Routes are countless.
Safety is foremost.
With unregulated driving,
your loved ones might end up in tears.
Shut up, stupid!
Move it!
Hu Kou! Detach!
Hu Kou!
I feel dizzy.
Top priority from UEG,
to all standby forces on Earth.
Due to Jupiter's gravitational spike,
a total of 4,771 Earth Engines
have shut down globally.
To avoid collision with Jupiter,
every unit must execute Emergency
Protocol No. 3 and depart immediately.
It's imperative to restart
all malfunctioning engines within 36 hours.
This rescue mission
concerns the survival of 3.5 billion human lives.
This mission is to be above all else,
at any cost.
Rescue units are on the go!
In order to expedite the rescue,
all resources will be consolidated.
The space station will be
implementing a low consumption mode.
Lisa, low consumption mode implemented.
Regular communication services
will be cut off shortly.
Low consumption mode activated.
I just got here.
How could I know about hibernation?
MOSS, please contact my relative.
Contact Liu Qi.
Liu Qi isn't in the allocated living area.
Connection failed.
MOSS. Contact transporter driver Han Ziang.
Incoming connection.
Peiqiang? Is that you?
Father. It's me.
Have you seen Liu Qi?
Liu Qi is right here with me.
We just ran into an earthquake.
We are on the outside surface now.
MOSS. Locate the transporter
and guide it to the nearest refuge center.
What's there to say to him?
Transporter 373. Driver Han Ziang.
Please proceed to Jinan No. 5 refuge center.
Space station flight configuration completed.
All personnel, enter hibernation
for energy conservation.
Hibernation rate at 77.3%.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang,
please proceed towards hibernation unit quickly.
Low consumption mode activated.
Consolidation of all resources to
expedite global rescue mission.
Initiating global surface scan
and complete network coverage.
What's this?
Emergency communication
authorization code of Liu Qi's dad.
It's a direct line to the space station.
Transporter 373.
Please slow down and stop.
Await for further instructions.
Transporter 373,
stay still and await instructions.
Hey!
Transporter 373.
This is an emergency requisition.
Stop now!
Transporter 373.
I swear.
That girl from the day before.
She was totally voluntary!
Shut up!
They are not here to take you back.
We are rescue team, unit CN171-11,
assigned to aim for Hangzhou 01 Earth Engine.
In accordance with The Wandering Earth Act,
Article 32, Section 1,
your transporter and crew
have been requisited.
To save the cargo container,
their driver decoupled his transporter
and went down the crevasse.
and sacrificed himself.
What's inside?
What could be that important?
Boss! Cargo container has been reloaded.
Engineers, check on the Lighter Core.
Zhou Qian, reorganize the transporter crew.
- Move out as soon as possible!
- Roger that.
Lighter Core.
Isn't that the Earth Engine's trigger device?
No Earth Engine has shut down
for the past 30 years.
It's not just a simple rescue mission.
A lot of people will die.
Boss! Lighter Core self-check completed.
Everything is normal.
Please assist sub-mission 1125.
Deliver the Lighter Core
and restart Hangzhou Earth Engine.
Clear the road.
Let the team with the Lighter Core pass first.
Captain Wang from unit 171-11.
Our destination is Nanjing.
Don't wait for us, please move forward.
Copy that. Wish you the best.
Unit 171-01,
we're entering Shanghai area.
Report road status.
Tectonic plate movements sourced in Shanghai area.
Proceed with caution.
Roger that.
Boss! Look!
Our home.
What happened to it?
Liu Zi, report 171's locations.
Unit 06's signal was last received at Cangzhou.
Units 09, 13, and 15 signals
were last received at Huaian.
Other units have made it to Shanghai area
and are on their way to Hangzhou.
- Boss.
- You guys go take a look.
- Roger that.
- Yes, sir.
Liu Zi, scout.
Our team is up ahead,
distance estimated 80 km.
Follow the crevasse.
We should rendezvous within an hour.
This place looks unstable.
Pass through as soon as possible.
- Load up. Move out.
- Roger.
Engineer team, stay alert.
This is unit 171-11.
We have entered Shanghai area.
Unit 11, be alert.
We've received a distress signal.
- Please check the surrounding environment.
- Copy that.
01. 01. Collapsed subway ahead.
Please detour.
Copy that.
Duoduo.
Don't be afraid.
This was Grandpa's home.
Look at those tall buildings.
A lot of people used to live there.
Back then,
no one cared about the Sun.
Everyone was concerned
about the thing that is called money.
Grandpa couldn't make a lot of money back then.
But I was happy every day.
Especially on my way home.
I could always smell your grandma's cooking
from far away.
Actually, she could barely cook
except for the scallion noodles.
I tell you,
Her scallion noodles
are incredibly salty.
But I slurped it all up,
cleaned my bowl every time.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
Lieutenant Colonel Makarov.
Please initiate hibernation mode
as soon as possible.
Don't worry,
your son will be safe.
MOSS.
Where is Liu Qi now?
Why are they in Shanghai?
Transporter 373
has been integrated into the rescue mission
on their way to Hangzhou 01 Earth Engine.
Who's in command?
Request to connect with the commander.
Incoming connection.
Captain Wang Lei.
This is the space station.
I am astronaut Liu Peiqiang.
Hello, Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
I'm the unit commander for CN171-11.
Please instruct.
Captain Wang Lei.
Within protocols,
please resettle the civilians
into the nearest underground city quickly.
Lieutenant Liu Peiqiang.
We have an urgent rescue mission.
Thanks for your understanding.
I'll resettle the civilians
at the Jiaxing refuge center,
but the transporter
has a special operating system.
We need driver Han Ziang to stay.
Over.
Captain Wang Lei.
This is a dangerous rescue mission.
- Please ensure the safety of Han Ziang.
- I stay! I can drive this transporter, too.
When we arrive at Jiaxing,
let Grandpa and the others get off.
You can operate shit.
Just follow the orders!
Captain Wang Lei, he is still a kid.
He is not capable--
What rights do you have to make decisions for me?
My mom's death
was your decision.
Liu Qi, what are you talking about?
Am I wrong?
After I left,
only one custodian can accompany
Liu Qi into underground city.
She's gravely ill, she won't hold up much longer.
Giving up on the treatment.
This is the only way to ensure
both of you and Liu Qi
can survive.
That's enough. I get it.
So be it.
Father.
Sorry.
Mayday!
Atmospheric pressure is dropping.
We are unable to maintain airborne.
Air force rescue unit CN114-03. Force landing!
Mayday!
Atmospheric pressure is dropping.
MOSS, what's the status on Earth?
Jupiter's gravitational spike detected.
All surface communications
in Shanghai area were lost.
All alert!
An object is crashing to our rear!
MOSS,
report surface status!
Due to Jupiter's gravitational spike,
the Earth is experiencing global aftershocks.
Tectonic plates are fracturing in Asia and Pacific.
The glass...
The glass is going to crack.
Oh, my God!
Am I going to die here?
Death is normal.
What?
All units! Helmets on!
What are you doing?
Let go!
Go away!
Two hundred meters ahead!
Collapse alert!
Full speed reverse!
Move!
Extreme turbulences at Earth's atmosphere.
Global disaster loss assessment completed.
Point formation flight terminated.
Loading evacuation procedures.
What? Evacuation?
MOSS, connect me to UEG.
Hibernation gas releasing.
Evacuation procedure. Hibernate immediately.
MOSS, open the cabin!
Open the cabin, MOSS!
This is defection!
Help!
I don't want to die here!
Didn't you say death was normal?
Help!
Boss.
We've lost contact with the other units.
I can't reach them!
Da Gang, transport the Lighter Core with me!
Chui Zi, Ya Tou, save the others.
Liu Zi, find a way out!
Everyone, abandon the vehicle!
Yes!
Go!
Get in!
Quick! Get in, quick!
Help!
What's going on?
How are you guys doing?
- Stay calm. We'll get you out now.
- Hurry up!
Normal.
Old man, quick on feet.
Boss, the Lighter Core is in good condition.
Still hauling this damn ball now?
Among all the Lighter Cores
that were meant for Hangzhou,
This is the last one.
We've lost all our units.
This Lighter Core is Hangzhou's only hope.
Nice speech.
But what about the two kids here?
Boss, this building looks intact.
We can try to climb up from inside.
Good.
Let's get the Lighter Core out now.
- Liu Zi, find a way out.
- Roger.
Gang Zi. Zhou Qian. Load the Lighter Core.
Hold on.
Load people first.
Load
people.
Stop wasting time.
Load the Lighter Core and people together!
Slow down.
I have acrophobia.
Boss. I found an opening.
We can't use dynamite here!
This building is crumbling.
Chui Zi. Liu Zi. Whoever here! Make a way out!
Ya Tou, you take over.
Hu Kou! Grandpa!
Hurry up!
Gang Zi, report the position of the Lighter Core.
50th floor. Below Han Ziang!
Here it is!
Right here! The thinnest part!
Thin? What thin?
- I'll leave this to you.
- Okay.
The pulley can't hold longer.
Pull up the Lighter Core.
Are you okay, old man?
Leave me! Go up quickly!
- Go up quickly.
- Wang Lei! Pull my grandfather up!
Gang Zi. Position.
Lighter Core is now on the 75th floor.
Quick!
Old man!
Get up here, you old man!
Wang Lei, I can't hold it any more!
Old man!
Let me go, kid.
Grandpa!
Gang Zi!
Boss.
Gang Zi is gone.
Stop dazing.
Han Ziang is gone.
Get them two out of here.
Liu Qi.
- Duoduo, let's move.
- Liu Qi.
Hu Kou.
Are you and Duoduo
- safe?
Old man.
Let's go.
Where are you, old man?
I'm coming to get you.
Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Grandpa.
Hu Kou, save Grandpa!
Liu Qi, you save Grandpa!
Where are you, old man?
OXYGEN: 1%
On the 17th day after the Earth stopped spinning,
I saved a child.
She was handed over to me by countless hands.
I don't know who her parents were.
Every soul under the water
is her mother and father.
I named her Han Duoduo.
I named her after my daughter.
Grandpa!
I am so sorry, old man.
My grandchildren.
- Don't be afraid.
- Come up now!
From then on,
we are a family.
Hu Kou.
As a brother,
you have to watch over your sister.
Take Duoduo home.
Grandpa!
Duoduo.
- It's dangerous.
- Duoduo.
- Step back.
Why didn't you save my grandpa?
This is our fate!
Let my brother go!
Duoduo.
- Chui Zi, Ya Tou, take them away.
- Roger.
Don't touch her.
Duoduo, it's dangerous.
Stop moving.
You will both freeze to death here!
I'm not leaving with you.
I'm going home with my brother.
Boss, if we march to Hangzhou at full speed,
it should take us three hours to get to Hangzhou.
The transporter is gone.
I'm no use to you anymore.
Leave them with the backup supplies
and a military navigation!
Let's move!
Hangzhou awaits.
Duoduo, let's go home.
Grandpa is gone.
Where is our home?
Warning. Unauthorized awakening.
Hibernation mode compromised.
By the contingency regulations,
activating manual rectification procedure.
Awakening personnel of unit H-7X01.
Lieutenant Colonel Makarov.
Lieutenant Colonel Hamdan.
According to contingency regulations,
please rectify accidental awakening.
Incident No. H-71.
According to contingency regulations,
please rectify accidental awakening.
Incident No. H-71.
Liu Peiqiang.
What are you doing?
The space station has ran off track!
Earth's communications will soon be paralyzed.
People on Earth are abandoned.
My son is still out there!
Have you lost your mind? Because of your son?
We're in low consumption mode.
You will be handed over to the military court!
Low consumption mode is a ruse!
See it for yourself.
Perhaps MOSS is malfunctioning.
It's defection!
What are you planning to do?
Head to the central control module.
Stop the space station.
Will all violators
stop contact immediately with Earth
and return to the hibernation area?
Liu, are you sure we have to go via this airlock?
Makarov, maybe you shouldn't come with me.
You won't make it without me.
Do you think you know the exterior like I do?
Don't forget...
We Russians invented space station 100 years ago.
The airlock isn't designed for exiting.
Are you sure this is going to work?
I'm sure.
We want to take our kids
to go salmon fishing on Lake Baikal.
I'd rather have hotpot in Chongqing.
The central control module is coming.
Russian cosmonauts are invincible in the space.
Grab me, Liu Peiqiang!
I don't want to die!
Makarov!
Quick! Pull quickly!
Go.
It's probably much better to just sleep
in the hibernation unit.
Jupiter has captured Earth's atmosphere.
Oh, my God!
Over there!
The distress signal is coming from there.
Even the plane of the air rescue unit has crashed.
An intact transporter...
Should be the source of the distress signal.
I'll check the transporter.
You all go onboard for shelter.
Search for anything useful.
Come on!
Liu Qi!
Come on! I'm going to kill her!
Come over, quick!
You! Calm down!
We are also a rescue unit.
It's okay.
Calm down.
The mission of our air force rescue unit
is to restart the Torque Engines along the equator.
But Jupiter's gravitational force
has thinned out our atmosphere.
The aircraft can't fly anymore.
I don't even know how many aircraft can survive.
Thanks.
Calm yourself.
Talk to us after you eat.
Aren't all of you a rescue unit from China?
Why is there a foreigner in your unit?
Who's a foreigner?
My father is from Beijing.
I am an authentic
Chinese.
This transporter is functioning.
That's good news.
We can go home.
Man, you can operate this transporter?
Yes. And?
Everyone. We've got to hurry. Time is ticking.
Re-establishing data connection
for submission 0051.
Mission object. Sulawesi 03 Torque Engine.
We have a Lighter Core on board.
The mission has to continue.
I'm the commander of the rescue unit CN171-11.
Our unit has to reactivate
Hangzhou 01 Earth Engine.
Anyone copy?
Please reply!
Magma has leaked into Hangzhou underground city.
There are 350,000 people trapped.
Our Lighter Core is their only hope.
Does anyone copy?
Can't handle that much.
The engines along the equator
are the most important rescue target.
Even if we drive non-stop,
it'll take more than ten hours to get there.
Fortunately, you guys showed up.
Han Ziang, senior driver.
Beijing No. 3 Transportation Division reminds you.
Routes are countless.
Safety is foremost.
With unregulated driving,
your loved ones might end up in tears.
Boss.
Hangzhou underground city is destroyed.
Huang Ming!
Unload the battery pack.
Poor kid.
He froze to death.
Huang Ming!
Check the status of the Lighter Core,
and keep moving.
- Boss!
- Boss! We no longer have a target!
- Keep moving, am I clear?
- What's the point?
This Lighter Core is the hope
of 350,000 people in Hangzhou.
But they are dead now.
Zhou Qian!
No more death!
Yes, no more death.
But Han Ziang. Gang Zi! Huang Ming!
And all those lives of our rescue
unit had died in vain.
3.5 billion lives on Earth.
My wife and child! All died in vain!
Boss.
Bro.
Think carefully.
It's our only chance to go home.
What?
No one is forcing you.
You can switch with them anytime.
Attention to all members of rescue unit CN171-11.
Rescue mission has failed.
Disband unit now.
All of you
may return home now.
Boss, where are you going?
There's a Lighter Core onboard.
Rescue unit CN171-11.
Please assist us
to rescue Sulawesi.
Everyone, our mission is to restart
Sulawesi 03 Torque Engine.
Only a handful of Lighter Core
can make it to the equator now.
The survival of Earth is counting on us.
Who are you? Where did you come from?
Li Yiyi.
Emergency technical observer of UEG
Such a high rank for someone so young.
When this is over...
I will settle with you
for what happened to my grandpa.
Head South. We're going to Sulawesi.
Will all violators
stop contact with Earth immediately
and return to hibernation area.
Man, I've got to correct you.
It will take more than 2,500 years
for the frozen Lake Baikal to liquefy.
That's okay.
We have children.
And their children will have children.
There'll be a day
when ice turns into water.
There's another 20 to 30 meters
till A3 intersection.
Look! A1 intersection exploded.
Maybe there are others who discovered
about the defection too.
And they are also trying to
make their way to the central control module.
Makarov,  follow me.
Hurry! Climb quickly!
Watch out.
Mom. I want to go home!
Liu Peiqiang!
This is just one more module
away from A3 intersection.
Let's jump.
The central control module is coming.
Jump!
Primary threat detected.
Unbarring lethal countermeasures.
Grab me! Makarov!
Makarov!
Liu!
I do believe in your words.
There'll be a day
when ice turns into water.
Let's take our children
to go salmon fishing at that time.
MOSS! That's homicide!
Warning. Airlock N-03 is offline.
Unauthorized entry.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
Your actions
are in violation of the Wandering Earth Act.
Article 5, Section 24.
You are deprived of all authority.
MANUAL CONTROL INVALID
Every action of the space station is legal
and fully authorized by the UEG.
MOSS never defected.
But to executing authorized orders.
We will soon cross the Terminator.
Once crossed,
it's the dark side of Earth.
Rescue unit JP 041-02
restarted Osaka 03 Earth Engine.
This is rescue unit CN189-03.
Kashgar 01 Earth Engine restarted.
Team RU212 reporting.
Sochi 01 Earth Engine has restarted.
NO 013-01 reporting.
Turin 02 Earth Engine has restarted.
Rescue unit HR011-08 reporting.
Singapore 02 Earth Engine has restarted.
Everyone. 90 percent of the Torque Engines
have been reactivated.
The Sulawesi ones are the only ones left.
We will replenish at the supply depot ahead.
Okay.
Five minutes till top up.
That's a big fellow.
Is that a whale?
Maybe.
Why is it here?
Had swum this far.
It should be heading home.
Heading home?
Once this mission is completed,
you can reunite with your father.
When I was a child,
someone told me that
he would be a star in the sky.
Whenever I lift my head, I'll be able to see him.
Later, I realized it was all lie.
In Beijing
there's no star to be seen.
Actually, in my heart,
that star has vanished since a long time ago.
Grandpa asked me
to watch over my little sister
and take Duoduo home.
I must
take Duoduo home.
Earth Engines have restarted.
Saturated rescue.
Other units arrived before us.
Have we succeeded?
These are the last remaining Torque Engines.
All has been reactivated now.
We did it.
Once the readings rise back to normal
we can all go home.
The distance to Jupiter is still decreasing.
Only 0.42 second after activating
Emergency Protocol No. 3.
MOSS has already
deduced out all possible outcomes.
UEG was informed
but still chose to perform this rescue mission,
which was predetermined to be futile.
The evacuation of space station
indicated that the rescue mission has failed.
After three hours
Earth will breach Jupiter's Roche limit
and begin the inevitable disintegration process.
MOSS will announce a global broadcast.
Fifteen.
Fourteen.
Thirteen.
Twelve.
The Wandering Earth project has failed.
The Earth Navigation project
renamed as
Helios project.
This is the Navigation Platform
international space station,
transmitting the final broadcast to the world.
In the past 36 hours,
mankind experienced the biggest threat
to human survival.
Over 1.5 million rescue personnels
from around the globe.
Propulsion Engines 71%
Torque Engines 100%
have been fully reactivated.
Unfortunately,
Jupiter's gravitational pull
has surpassed the combined power of all engines.
The Earth has missed
its last chance of escape.
In order to sustain human civilization,
MOSS will initiate the Helios project.
300,000 human embryos are stored on
the Navigation Platform space station,
along with 100 million seeds of basic crops,
DNA maps of all known animals
and planet species,
and digital libraries
of all human civilizations
to ensure the successful revival
of new hosted planet.
Stop robbing!
We're all going to die.
You are all heroes of the Earth.
We will remember
to honor you.
We will shoulder
your aspirations
and send it to our new home,
2,500 years.
Everything will come to an end
in the last seven days
before Earth collides with Jupiter.
Let us go home.
Hug your parents.
Kiss your beloved partner and children.
Gather with the family
for a proper goodbye.
Good luck to you.
End of broadcast.
Farewell.
Hu Kou, I want to go home.
Seven days?
Within a day, our atmosphere
would be drained empty.
Everyone will die of asphyxiation.
Where are the seven days?
Members of the CN171-11
rescue unit, move onboard.
Be ready to evacuate.
Screw you, damn Jupiter!
Screw you!
Please get ready,
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
MOSS will assist you to return to
the backup hibernation unit.
MOSS, I have an emergency
communication authorization.
Code 5711 6231 0501
Let me speak to my son for the last time.
Liu Qi is not in his designated area.
Connection unavailable.
Han Ziang is not at his designated transporter.
The connection is unavailable.
Wang Lei is not at his designated transporter.
The contact with Transporter 373 was lost.
Its last transmission was from Shanghai area.
I can no longer recall your face, you bastard.
Jupiter is right in front of me.
When are you coming back?
From the day when
the Wandering Earth Project was initiated
there was no turning back.
Look!
It's Jupiter.
The largest planet in the Solar System.
Dad, there is an eye on Jupiter.
That's not an eye.
That's a huge Windstorm on Jupiter.
Jupiter
is like a huge balloon.
Composed of 90%...
Hydrogen!
Li Yiyi.
The mix of Jupiter's and Earth's atmospheres,
is it combustible?
By now, Jupiter has siphoned
at least 30 billion liters of oxygen.
The combustion shockwave will be over 1,000 Mach.
The generated force will
be sufficient to push Earth away.
A hydrogen and oxygen mixture will be
combustible with just a single match.
All we need is a match.
No, the distance between two planets
is over 70,000 km.
Not even intercontinental ballistic missile
can reach that far!
Li Yiyi.
What about this match?
What match?
I can modify the engine's operating system
to blast the beam much higher!
Wang Lei.
Jupiter's combustion shockwave
can propel Earth out from Jupiter.
I am listening.
Don't yell.
Come on. Let's light up Jupiter!
That's mutual annihilation.
Better than waiting to die.
Anyone who wants to quit?
The Helios project's evacuation
procedure is initiated.
All rescue units...
All rescue units are evacuating.
Calling Navigation Platform international
space station. Do you copy?
Repeat, calling Navigation Platform space station.
We have a new plan.
Please respond.
All communications have been shielded.
Attention, everyone.
We only got 30 minutes.
This mission has three steps.
Step one. Shut down engine
to gain control.
Each Earth Engine has 7 nozzles.
I'll shut down the engine temporarily
and direct all energy into one nozzle
to generate a plasma beam that
could reach high enough.
Does anyone recall the famous 12 Chimes of Spring?
I wrote that program.
- That was you--
- Boring, I know.
I'm going to use it to override the system
so that we'll be able to take control.
Step two. Once we override the system,
the auto unlock mechanism would not function,
which means it has to be unlocked manually.
Captain Wang
and
Antennae
Scarface
Band-aid.
- My name is--
- Whatever.
The manual unlocking task
is depending on you guys.
The last step, load the Lighter Core
into the reaction chamber
to reignite the Earth Engine.
Blast the plasma beam 70,000 km up into the space
and light up Jupiter.
The combustion shockwave from the explosion
- will travel along the atmospheric
transference back to the Earth.
Boom!
To propel Earth away.
Get it for me please.
Liu Qi, you'll drive the Lighter Core
to the reaction chamber.
The installation procedure
is basically automatic.
Chinese heart, you go with him.
Why am I involved?
Are you kidding?
Installing a Lighter Core
- requires a minimum of 13 months training.
You're welcome to take his place.
Once the mission is accomplished,
all head to the underground city immediately.
Bear in mind, it will be a very,
very
humongous wave.
This is a make or break move.
Assignment completed.
Any questions?
Excellent.
Hey.
There.
It's the control center.
Attention, all evacuating rescue units.
We need your assistance.
Please slow down and stop.
We need your support.
Looks like we are on our own now.
Oh, mighty Newton.
Enlightened Einstein.
Holy Hawking.
Also Amitabha Buddha.
Gang Zi will bless us.
I learned the installation procedure
at my internship.
Don't forget, your brother is a genius.
Wait. We're executing an emergency mission.
We need your help.
It's all over.
Who cares?
I want to live a few more days!
Please help us.
You should evacuate!
Over here!
Captain Wang.
We're counting on you guys.
Don't worry.
Zhou Qian,
Take Duoduo upstairs to contact for reinforcement.
Roger that.
Duoduo, let's go.
Go.
The Earth Engine has been shut down.
Fellows. Let's hit it!
It's fully automatic! What are you browsing at?
Why the manual is so thick if it's automatic?
What are you up to?
Shit!
I'd better delve into it.
The colors of wire cores are not random.
Red, white, blue, orange. All in sequence.
How come everything is in grey here?
This is for transporter's broadcast.
This is for connecting up there.
Press to speak.
- What's up there?
- Space station.
Come on. Next.
Uploading trojan 12 Chimes of Spring.
This is rescue unit CN171-11 from China.
Current location, Sulawesi 03 Torque Engine.
We're executing our last rescue mission.
Why are these people still trying?
It's a waste of time. Don't bother.
Rescue unit CN171-11.
We have a new plan.
Calling for reinforcement!
We're the rescue unit CN171-11.
- I am craving for a bowl of rice.
- We still have the last rescue mission.
Would be even better if there's miso soup.
We're done with the last one.
What's next?
One moment.
Should be fully automatic.
Next step is manual labor.
The program he wrote does not include
the percussion pin procedure.
You called this
a pin?
No rescue units responding.
Nobody is responding.
What is Error 425?
What does it mean?
Li Yiyi!
How is it fully automatic?
Have I handed the manual to you?
It's for mishaps like this.
What is mishap 425?
Read it yourself.
Warning. Han Ziang illegally operating...
You are a mishap.
Tim. Helmet on!
Wait!
Forget about it!
What's next?
Fully automatic.
Isn't it supposed to be fully automatic?
Why is it stuck here?
Without any hardware tweak
you'll be hacking shit!
Let me pass.
Hu Kou, where are you?
I'm not getting any response.
There's so much space left!
Makes me feel better crossing over you!
You are really boring, do you know that?
This freaking door is jammed.
Here.
Lao He. How can you fix it
without a contingency diagram?
Shut up! Let me concentrate!
The jumpers here weren't touched for decades.
With one mistake, it's game over.
SON. IT'S COLD DON'T FORGET
YOUR LONG JOHNS. MOM
Li Yiyi, is the Ignitor ready?
No. It is displaying installation incomplete.
Looks like it's almost done.
Liu Qi!
Liu Qi! Are you crazy?
Save your words.
Get out and help.
Warning. Temperature regulator fails.
Overload.
Electricity remaining at 30%.
Both of you all right?
Band-aid.
Duoduo. Can you move?
One, two, three, hold on.
Liu Qi.
Have you found the problem?
It's stuck inside.
Li Yiyi.
Go on. Go!
Duoduo, leave me here.
Hurry up and evacuate to the underground city.
Warning! Overheat!
Thermal suit, low power.
Liu Qi! You'll be squeezed to death!
Help!
Can anyone help us?
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang
Please follow MOSS' instructions.
back to the backup hibernation unit.
Uncle Liu Peiqiang.
It's Han Duoduo.
We still have hope.
Duoduo.
Duoduo. Are you okay?
Is Liu Qi still there?
We are all here.
We are at Sulawesi 03 Torque Engine.
We will light up Jupiter
to propel Earth away.
We need reinforcement.
Unfortunately, seven hours ago,
this plan had already been
proposed by Israeli scientists.
The probability of success is zero.
Don't worry, Duoduo.
I will try to contact UEG.
Details of the plan have been uploaded.
This is the United Earth Government.
State your identity immediately
to acknowledge this transmission.
United Earth Government.
I'm Chinese astronaut Liu Peiqiang.
Please send a global order now
to deploy all rescue units in the vicinity
of Sulawesi for reinforcements.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
During these last moments
of Earth's collision with Jupiter,
tasking personnel to perform a mission
with zero probability of success
while forsaking the opportunity of them
to reunite with their loved ones
is an order
we cannot pass down.
Today
it's the first day of Chinese New Year.
It was meant to be a day of reunion.
As a father,
I don't want this to be the last reunion.
I refuse to yield.
There is nothing we cannot lose.
For the sake of our children...
I beg you.
As the United Earth Government,
we cannot accept your request.
However,
as a private individual,
I will connect the rescue unit
to the global broadcasting system.
And the rest
will be up to the will of each individual.
Hello, people from every rescue unit.
My name is Han Duoduo.
I'm a junior high school student.
Our rescue unit is executing our final mission.
Right now, I'm extremely terrified.
My legs are trembling.
Everybody in my unit is teething
and nailing and making every possible effort.
But there is nothing I can do to help!
Yesterday, my teacher asked us,
"What is hope?"
In the past
I never believed in hope.
But now, I do.
I believe that for our time,
hope is precious like a diamond.
Hope.
Hope is the only way to guide us home.
Please come back and fight together!
Light up Jupiter! Save our Earth!
We are at Sulawesi 03 Torque Engine.
Under the command of Captain Wang Lei.
Chinese rescue unit CN171-11.
Han Duoduo.
End of broadcast.
The global broadcast is over.
I want to go home
to see my mother.
If Earth is destroyed,
there'll be nobody left to see!
We're turning back!
Let's go!
We're unlikely to make it home within seven days.
Why are we returning then?
Coordinate located.
Communication frequency channel 055 0311.
Connecting to Sulawesi 03
secondary communication network.
Covering the entire frequency.
Sharing the plan for engine overriding.
All rescue units, please adjust the projection
directions of 14 Torque Engines to Jupiter's Apex.
Tim!
Pull faster!
I'm pulling!
I can't pull it!
Pull me out!
You are too heavy!
Tim
Tim!
Fuck this shit.
No fucking way!
Pull faster!
No!
Liu Qi! Pull me up!
I don't want to die!
Lao He!
The reaction chamber is ready!
Are you done or what?
Life and death are normal.
Lao He!
You did it!
Lao He?
Liu Qi! Tim! Get out now!
Liu Qi! Speed up!
Captain Wang.
The engine is ready for ignition.
We only have 15 minutes left!
Japanese rescue unit CPL Sato Ryuichi, report!
Russian rescue unit PFC Ivan, report!
Soldier Brian from UK rescue unit, report!
Hurry!
Everyone, on my mark!
One.
Two.
Push.
One.
Two.
Push.
Captain Wang,
hold it right there!
Liu Qi! Ready for ignition!
Get out!
Door! Open for me!
Open it!
Shut up!
Shut up and hurry!
Hurry up!
Mom, I want to go home!
Li Yiyi!
Ignite!
Coming!
8,000 km.
7,000 km.
Another 6,000 km.
Reaching explosive range!
Maximum height achieved.
Still
5,000 km short.
What? Li Yiyi!
Think of something!
Sulawesi 03 Engine.
Singapore 01 Engine.
Jakarta 04 Engine.
All 3 plasma beams have failed to
reach the explosive range.
Everyone! Hang on!
We cannot hold any longer.
FUEL REMAINING: 300,014.9
There's another way.
Liu Qi! Wang Lei! We still have a chance!
Hang on!
United Earth Government.
The Navigation Platform space station
contains 300,000 tons of fuel.
Request to collide into the plasma beam.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
The goal of the Wandering Earth Project
is to maximize the survival of mankind.
The Helios Project ensures
the continuity of human civilization.
We need more time to discuss it.
We're running out of time!
A civilization without men
is meaningless.
COMMUNICATION FAIL
PROGRAM TERMINATED
As the operating system of Helios Project,
MOSS will not permit any form of action
to sacrifice the Navigation Platform.
FIRE EXTINGUISHING
SYSTEM SHUTDOWN
Do you know why alcohol
was banned in space during Gagarin's time?
Happy New Year!
Data error. Core node unavailable.
MANUAL CONTROL OVERRIDING
It is unreasonable
to expect humans to stay reasonable.
Going home.
Reconnect with UEG.
Lieutenant Colonel Liu Peiqiang.
This is the United Earth Government.
We have decided
to choose hope.
Regardless of the outcome
for the history of mankind,
we shall respectfully accept it.
Best of luck to you.
Best of luck to Earth.
Earth
will survive.
Depart the hibernation units.
Standby for impact.
Activating evacuation procedure
for hibernation units.
United Earth Government.
Inform all personnel on the surface
to seek emergency refuge.
Forward three.
Chinese rescue unit CN171-11.
This is the space station.
I'm Liu Peiqiang.
The space station has 300,000 tons of fuel.
The explosion radius
will reach a range over 5,000 km.
Igniting space station
can ignite Jupiter.
Liu Peiqiang!
What are you doing?
Wang Lei!
Release now!
Captain Wang Lei.
Don't let go.
Shut up, Liu Peiqiang!
- This is an order!
- Copy.
Wang Lei! You bastard!
- Liu Qi.
- Li Yiyi!
Shut down Earth Engine!
- Liu Qi.
- Shut up!
Son!
Shut up.
My son.
I'm sorry.
Dad is going on a mission again.
This is the most important mission
in Dad's life.
You said that
when I can see Jupiter,
you'll be back.
You lied.
You were four years old when I left.
And now...
you are a grown man.
Dad used to tell you that
Dad is up in the sky.
Just lift your head
and you'd be able to see me.
This time,
I promise you'll see me.
Come on.
Son.
Three,
two,
one.
Dad.
Jupiter.
Jupiter has been ignited.
The shockwave will reach Earth
in 7 minutes 13 seconds!
The survival of Earth is counting on this!
Hu Kou.
Evacuate everyone to the underground city!
Where are you, Hu Kou?
Liu Qi!
Liu Qi! Come back!
Duoduo needs you!
This way. Hurry up.
Hurry up. Get in!
Li Yiyi. Hurry!
Hurry back, Hu Kou! I'll wait for you
at the backup elevator.
Zhou Qian bled too much.
Evacuate now! I'm heading to the backup elevator
to pick up the others!
Five minutes left!
Get down now! This is an order!
Roger!
Ahh!
Duoduo! Watch out!
Boss!
Duoduo!
She's here!
- Duoduo.
- Get Duoduo out of here!
I can't hold on any longer.
Backup elevator collapsed.
Li Yiyi, do you have any other way?
Wang Lei.
Li Yiyi!
Hurry up and think of something!
Earth Engine!
We can try hiding under the Earth Engine!
If the thrust of the Earth Engine
can counteract the force of the shockwave.
There's still hope for you guys!
Liu Qi!
I'm not getting out for sure.
Go now!
Liu Qi!
Go!
Hurry!
All members of rescue unit CN171-11.
Attention.
This is
an order.
Live on.
Boss!
Liu Qi! Duoduo!
The transporter.
The transporter is falling down!
We
finally made it!
Warning. Low temperature.
Warning. Please check helmet's seal.
Brother.
Help.
Tim! Get down here!
Right away!
Help us!
Earth
survived.
The Sun
is located at the Milky Way's Orion arm.
Its mass constitutes 99.68% of the Solar System.
Now, the core of the Sun is rapidly
degenerating and expanding.
Earth will be engulfed.
To survive, mankind began
a groundbreaking project to maneuver
the entire planet to a new home
located 4.2 light years away.
I miss you all so badly!
The project is divided into five phases.
Phase one. Mankind will devote every resource
to construct 10,000 thrusters for
Earth's propulsion, called the Earth Engines.
Along with 10,000 underground cities
to protect human lives.
Stay right there!
Phase two. Activating the Torque Engines
encircled along the equator
to stop Earth's rotation.
A non-rotating Earth
will create mega tsunamis that would
sweep through the planet.
Eradicating half of the global population.
I'm all set and ready to go!
If there is no accident.
Phase three.
The Earth will use the gravitational force
of the Sun and Jupiter
- for final acceleration.
Embarking on
a voyage of wandering.
Will your sister come along?
Screw you!
After all these years,
still the same line?
Phase four.
When Earth departs from the Solar System,
Earth Engines will turn on in full power.
Spending 500 years to accelerate to 0.5%
of the speed of light.
Then gliding for 1,300 years.
After that, reversing Earth Engines' directions,
spending another 700 years
for deceleration.
Liu Hu Kou!
Where have you been?
Why is Li Yiyi here, too?
Phase five.
Earth begins to berth
at the targeted stellar system.
Arriving at our new home.
Becoming a new planet
of the targeted stellar system.
Don't you dare call me Hu Kou.
Where are your manners?
Call me brother.
Liu Qi.
Junior driver.
Beijing No. 3 Transportation Division reminds you.
Routes are countless.
Safety is foremost.
With unregulated driving,
your loved ones might end up in tears.
Driving rules violated, deduct three points.
Can you drive? Liu Hu Kou!
Li Yiyi! You're distracting
my vision with that bag!
My fault?
How am I blocking your vision
when I'm sitting behind you?
This project will last for 100 generations.
We are unaware of what the new Sun
at 4.2 light years away
will bring to our new home though.
But from this day on,
the courage and perseverance of mankind
will be etched among the stars.
This long voyage of hope and despair,
enduring 2,500 years through the cosmos,
is known as
the Wandering Earth Project.